mercyhurst.edu 2012-12-25

# Privacy Policy | Mercyhurst University

  * [Home](http://www.mercyhurst.edu/ "Home") » 
  * [About](http://www.mercyhurst.edu/about/ "About") » 
  * Privacy Policy

Mercyhurst College respects the privacy of all visitors to our Web site. Please review the following Privacy Policy to understand what information is being collected and how it will be used. Mercyhurst College will NOT make information collected available to any outside parties. All information gathered will be obtained only through your knowledge and consent.

## 1\. Use of Cookies

Cookies are small pieces of data passed from a Web site to your hard drive usually to enable some online services to work more efficiently or to make the use of services more convenient. Mercyhurst College will not use cookies to track and/or retain personally identifiable information without proper notification.

## 2\. Use of E-Mail

In spite of the good intentions of the college to respect the privacy of individuals, it should be understood that it is impossible to assure the privacy of e-mail. Not only may e-mail be sent to someone other than the intended recipient (either through mis-addressing or forwarding), but e-mail sent as plain text may also be intercepted as it travels over the network.

## 3\. Use of Forms

Mercyhurst College respects your privacy and does not condone providing any of your personal information to third parties without your permission, unless compelled by law or court order to do so, or to sell any personal information to third parties for purposes of marketing, advertising or promotion.

## 4\. Collection and Use of Information

In the course of visiting a Web site, Mercyhurst College permits the following information to be collected, stored and used:

### 4.1 Automatic Information Collected

This information is not to be reported or used in any manner that would reveal personally identifiable information or to be released to any outside (third) parties unless legally required.

### 4.1.1

Routing information such as IP address. Routing information is used to route the requested web page to your computer for viewing.

### 4.1.2

Essential technical information such as page accessed; time and date accessed; operating system used; type of browser used; information about the Web site from which you accessed the Mercyhurst College Web site. Essential technical information is used for such purposes as helping to respond to your request in an appropriate format and helping to plan Web site improvements.

## 5\. Limits to Privacy

The use of college resources, including computing and networking equipment and services, purchased with college funds, are intended for college business. While it is not the intention of the college to actively monitor communications or files stored or transmitted on college systems or devices, individuals must understand that under certain circumstances they may not have a right to privacy to such information. Such circumstances include but are not limited to: compliance with legal requirements or process; as part of an investigation of a suspected violation of law, regulation or college policy; to maintain the integrity of the college's computing systems.

## 6\. Freedom of Information Requests

Under the "Freedom of Information Act (FOIA)", except as otherwise provided by federal law or state statute, all records maintained or kept on file are considered public records and are subject to inspection by members of the public. As a member of the college community, your e-mail and any information collected in the course of visiting a Web site are considered public records and may be subject to Freedom of Information disclosure. In some cases e-mail messages about students may fall under the FERPA definition of 'education records' and therefore be subject to the provisions of FERPA regarding the release of the information and the student's right to inspect and review the information.

## 7\. Disclaimer

The Mercyhurst College Web site has many links to other Web sites. When you link to another site, you are no longer on the Mercyhurst College Web site and this privacy policy will not apply. When you link to another Web site, you are subject to the privacy policy of that new site.

Neither Mercyhurst College, nor any agency, officer or employee of Mercyhurst College warrants the accuracy, reliability or timeliness of any information published by this system, nor endorses any content, viewpoints, products or services linked from this system, and shall not be held liable for any losses caused by reliance on the accuracy, reliability or timeliness of such information. Portions of such information may be incorrect or not current. Any person or entity that relies on any information obtained from this system does so at their own risk.

Mercyhurst College reserves the right to revise and update this privacy policy at any time by posting such revised privacy policy on the Mercyhurst College home page.
